Zach Pruitt

1145 Century Park Ave. Kernersville, NC 27284 (336)414-0999 zjp4021@gmail.com

March 2017 to September 2019: Electrical & Landscaping Contractor, Self-Employed,

Winston-Salem, NC – Inspection of electrical equipment and systems to recognize defects, hazards and the requirement for repair modifications. Replacement and repair of electrical wiring, fixtures, equipment, and other miscellaneous systems in homes and small businesses.

December 2014 to November 2016: Retail Lending Fulfillment Supervisor I, Online Account

Opening, BB&T Winston Salem, NC – Managed team of 4 associates responsible for the production of Home Equity Lines of Credit originated through the BBT.com platform while focusing on client service, quality, compliance, process and risk management. Worked directly with external clients to resolve issues and complaints. Responsible for developing and coaching associates. Ensured business unit was compliant with Line of Business, State, and Federal regulatory requirements. Collaborated with various internal lines of business to identify, resolve, and implement appropriate levels of risk management and process improvement.

- Our team booked and funded 1525 applications for a total of \$86,550,000 in 2015
- Total loans booked and funded increased by 23% from 2014 to 2015
- Successfully implemented and began originating loans in Ohio, Pennsylvania and New Jersey
- Assisted in implementing a new Title and Settlement vendor

September 2013 to December 2014: Lending Process Analyst, Online Account Opening, BB&T

Winston Salem, NC – Responsible for analyzing business unit processes and procedures, and increasing lending efficiencies. Served as team lead and assisted with the processing, closing, booking and funding of Home Equity Loans and Lines of Credit through the BBT.com platform. Communicated directly with external clients to resolve issues and provide the perfect client experience throughout the loan process. Collaborated with internal partners and developed training materials and system enhancements that improved the quality and compliance of loan files, and overall client experience.

- Our team achieved record production for total dollars and number of loans booked in 2014
- Decreased outstanding loan exceptions from ~ 535 to less than 110
- Maintained an overall Package Error Rate well below Bank goal of 10%
- Promoted to Banking Officer
- Served as United Way Campaign Champion for Loan Services in 2014

January 2013 to September 2013: Leadership Associate, Leadership Development Program, BB&T

Winston Salem, NC – Completed a challenging leadership program that used a combination of classroom, case study, and on-the-job training experiences to develop associates and their skills. Responsible for learning and understanding core financial concepts, and credit and underwriting standards. Improved skills related to lending, leadership, negotiating, conflict resolution, self awareness, and managing interpersonal relationships.

- Won Award for Best Bank Performance-BB&T Bank Simulation
- Completed BB&T's Retail Academy

Volunteer

Experience

- United Way Young Leaders United, Forsyth County 2013-Present
- BB&T Lighthouse Project Team Lead 2014-2015
- Big Brothers Big Sisters of Forsyth County-Bowl For Kids' Sake Fundraiser 2014-Present
- Helping Hands Ministries, High Point, NC 2014-Present

Education

• University of North Carolina at Wilmington, May 2012 B.S. in Business Administration (Cum Laude), Concentration: Finance